<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting_started on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</title>
    <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/tags/getting_started/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting_started on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.hypriot.com/tags/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Docker on your Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 20:16:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Docker is a new technology that emerged in the last two years and took the software world by storm. What exactly is Docker and why did it became so popular in such short time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this guide is to answer these questions and to get you started with Docker on a Raspberry Pi in no time.
We are going to cover the procedure for Windows, OS X and Linux users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-heck-is-docker-and-why-would-i-use-it&#34;&gt;What the heck is Docker and why would I use it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker simplifies the packaging, distribution, installation and execution of (complex) applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this context, applications are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blogging platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com&#34;&gt;Wordpress &lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tools for software collaboration like &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/&#34;&gt;Gitlab&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://gogs.io/&#34;&gt;Gogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;file synchronization platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://owncloud.org/&#34;&gt;OwnCloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://seafile.com/en/home/&#34;&gt;Seafile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of applications usually consist of many components which need to be installed and configured. This is often a time consuming and frustrating experience for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker allows administrators or developers to package these applications into something called containers.
Containers are self-contained, preconfigured packages that a user can fetch and run with just a single command.
By keeping different software components separated in containers they can also be easily updated or removed without influencing each other.
There are many more advantages of using Docker; the details of which can be found in the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-raspberry-pi-an-easy-low-cost-way-of-getting-started-with-docker&#34;&gt;The Raspberry Pi: An easy, low cost way of getting started with Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we piqued your curiosity and you would like to dive into the magic world of Docker one of the easiest ways is by using Docker on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/help/what-is-a-raspberry-pi/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;.
According to the creators of the Raspberry Pi it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a low cost, credit-card sized computer that plugs into a computer monitor or TV, and uses a standard keyboard and mouse.
It is a capable little device that enables people of all ages to explore computing, and to learn how to program in languages like Scratch and Python.
It’s capable of doing everything you’d expect a desktop computer to do, from browsing the internet and playing high-definition video, to making spreadsheets, word-processing, and playing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this guide is to show you the necessary steps to get you started with Docker on a Raspberry Pi. Please follow the guide that covers your operating system and continue below once you have finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-windows-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;The Windows guide for setting up Docker on a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-mac-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;The Mac OS X guide for setting up Docker on a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-linux-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;The Linux guide for setting up Docker on a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-wild-with-docker-what-can-you-actually-do-with-it&#34;&gt;Going wild with Docker! What can you actually do with it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated in the beginning Docker simplifies the way software is distributed and run. We even said that you would only need one command for that. It is time to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just type &lt;code&gt;docker run&lt;/code&gt; into the terminal of your Raspberry Pi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -d -p 80:80 hypriot/rpi-busybox-httpd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command will download and start the Docker image &lt;em&gt;hypriot/rpi-busybox-httpd&lt;/em&gt; which contains a tiny webserver. Once an image is started it is called a &lt;em&gt;container&lt;/em&gt;. An image can also be used to start multiple containers.
You can check if your container is running by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker ps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see the container you just started in the container list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can open up your browser on your workstation and type in the IP address of your Raspberry Pi to see that it really works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/browser-pi-hypriot-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;hypriot-logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great aspect of running a Docker-based app is, you can be sure that it works on every machine running Docker with one exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we run Docker on a Raspberry Pi. So the CPU architecture here is &lt;strong&gt;ARM&lt;/strong&gt; rather than x86/x64 by Intel or AMD. Thus, Docker-based apps you use have to be packaged specifically for ARM architecture! Docker-based apps packaged for x86/x64 will not work and will result in an error such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;FATA[0003] Error response from daemon: Cannot start container 0f0fa3f8e510e53908e6a459e817d600b9649e621e7dede974d6a65761ad39e5: exec format error
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep this in mind when searching for apps on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/search?q=library&#34;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;the source&lt;/strong&gt; for Docker apps/images. If you see the keyword &lt;em&gt;RPI&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;ARM&lt;/em&gt; in the heading or description, this app can usually be used for the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We prepared a couple of &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/u/hypriot/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi ready images&lt;/a&gt; for your convenience. Try them out now and have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/search?q=hypriot&amp;searchfield=&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/dockerhub-hypriot-search.png&#34; alt=&#34;dockerhub-hypriot-search&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using Linux</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-linux-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 20:16:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-linux-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This guide shows you how to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using a &lt;strong&gt;Linux workstation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not read the getting started guide about Docker on the Raspberry Pi yet you might wanna check it out first: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device&#34;&gt;Getting started on your ARM device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to make this guide as concise as possible. Make sure that you know the basics about the command line and you should be ready to go.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t you can learn the basics in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/an-introduction-to-the-linux-terminal&#34;&gt;An Introduction to the Linux Terminal&lt;/a&gt; and come back afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;hardware&lt;/strong&gt; you gonna need to follow along is a Raspberry Pi 1 or 2 and one SD card.&lt;br /&gt;
If you are going to use a Raspberry 2 you will have to use a microSD card - otherwise a normal SD card is sufficient.
We recommend a size of at least 4 GB.&lt;br /&gt;
The SD card contains all the software which we are going to use on our Raspberry Pi.
With software we basically mean two things: first an operating system for your Raspberry Pi and second the software you as user would like to use - e.g. a browser or a word processing program.
In our case the software we wanna use is Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We - from Hypriot - created a preconfigured &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;SD card image&lt;/a&gt; which contains everything you need to run Docker on your Raspberry Pi.
To use the image you first have to download and transfer it to your SD card. Transferring an image to an SD card is often referred to as &lt;em&gt;flashing&lt;/em&gt;.
Afterwards you just have to insert the flashed SD card into your Raspberry Pi and start it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-the-hypriot-docker-sd-card-image&#34;&gt;Download the Hypriot Docker SD card image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our latest SD card image from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the download is completed open a terminal window. To do this use the search function of your Linux distribution and type &lt;em&gt;terminal&lt;/em&gt; and press &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we will extract the downloaded zip file. Go to your &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt; folder first by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/Downloads
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extract the zip file with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;unzip hypriot-rpi-201???.img.zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the file is unzipped you will have a new file with an &lt;strong&gt;.img&lt;/strong&gt; extension.
In the next step we will flash this file onto your SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flash-the-downloaded-image-to-your-sd-card&#34;&gt;Flash the downloaded image to your SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First put your SD card into the computer. Then in the terminal type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;lsblk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see a list of all your disks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/lsblk.png&#34; alt=&#34;lsblk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now identify the SD Card. Look at the fourth column which shows the size of the devices of your workstation.
One item in the list should have a size that is very close to the size of your SD card.
From there get the identifier which is shown in the first column.
In this case the identifier is &lt;code&gt;mmcblk0&lt;/code&gt; and 29,5G refers to a 32 GB sized SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you need to make sure that the partitions of the SD card are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; mounted.
Check the column &lt;em&gt;MOUNTPOINT&lt;/em&gt; – if you have any entries in the row of your SD card you need to unmount them.
If not you can skip the unmount command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the last screenshot we have to unmount one partition.
Copy and paste the path you see in your own &lt;em&gt;MOUNTPOINT&lt;/em&gt; column behind the &lt;code&gt;unmount&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;umount /run/media/mac/8734-1E4C
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are ready to flash the SD card. We are going to use the &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; command for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start make sure you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace the parameter &lt;code&gt;if=hypriot-rpi...&lt;/code&gt; with the path to the downloaded image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace the parameter &lt;code&gt;of=/dev/mmcblk0&lt;/code&gt; with the identifier of your SD card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dd if=hypriot-rpi-201???.img of=/dev/mmcblk0 bs=1M
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this command is executed you won&amp;rsquo;t get any information about its progress.
Depending on your hardware and the performance of your SD card it will take up to five minutes to flash the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; is finished you should get an output like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/after-dd.png&#34; alt=&#34;after-dd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally unmount the SD card again in the same way as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-raspberry-pi-with-the-sd-card&#34;&gt;Start your Raspberry Pi with the SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boot your Raspberry Pi by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting the Raspberry Pi to your local network via an ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;putting the SD card into the designated slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugging in the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the last step your Raspberry Pi will boot and the LEDs should start blinking.
The very first boot will take one to three minutes as the file system will be resized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ensure-everything-works&#34;&gt;Ensure everything works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if Docker is actually running we need to log into the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to find out the IP address of your Raspberry Pi first.
If you are not sure what the IP-Address of your PI is, there are different ways of finding it out.
One way is to use the tool &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; which you might need to install first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the Linux distribution you are using you need one of the following commands to install &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install nmap   # for debian based distros
yum install nmap       # for red hat based distros
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First identify the IP address of your own workstation. Type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hostname -I
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the following screenshot our IP address is &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.101&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/hostname-i.png&#34; alt=&#34;hostname-i&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then replace the IP address in front of the &lt;code&gt;/24&lt;/code&gt; with yours and type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -sP 192.168.0.101/24 | grep black-pearl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/nmap.png&#34; alt=&#34;nmap result of query&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; command should show you the IP address of your Raspberry Pi.
If you get a blank line without an IP address your Raspberry Pi is probably not connected to the network.
Or there is a problem with the SD card which prevents the Raspberry Pi from booting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you found out the IP address establish a connection to the Raspberry Pi with the ssh command.
Replace the IP address after the &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; with the one of your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh pirate@192.168.0.27
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are asked for the password type &lt;code&gt;hypriot&lt;/code&gt; and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you establish the connection you will be asked if you are sure that you want to connect to the Raspberry Pi - answer with &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything went fine you should now see the &lt;em&gt;HypriotOS&lt;/em&gt; command line prompt waiting for your input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/rpi-first-connect.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot docker first connection&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally check if the Docker service is running by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;docker info&lt;/code&gt; command should look similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/linux-screenies/docker-info.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot docker info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations! You have succeeded in getting Docker running on your Raspberry Pi!&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to continue your exploration of Docker with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device#going-wild-with-docker-what-can-you-actually-do-with-it:397c66ef19f9f061b6711d2e296cb276&#34;&gt;Getting Started Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-mac-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 20:16:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-mac-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This guide shows you how to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using a &lt;strong&gt;Mac OS X workstation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not read the getting started guide about Docker on the Raspberry Pi yet you might wanna check it out first: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device&#34;&gt;Getting started with Docker on your ARM Device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to make this guide as concise as possible. Make sure that you know the basics about the command line and you should be ready to go.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t you can learn the basics in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/an-introduction-to-the-linux-terminal&#34;&gt;An Introduction to the Linux Terminal&lt;/a&gt; and come back afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;hardware&lt;/strong&gt; you gonna need to follow along is a Raspberry Pi 1 or 2 and one SD card.
If you are going to use a Raspberry 2 you will have to use a microSD card - otherwise a normal SD card is sufficient.
We recommend a size of at least 4 GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SD card contains all the software which we are going to use on our Raspberry Pi.
With software we basically mean two things: first an operating system for your Raspberry Pi and second the software you as user would like to use - e.g. a browser or a word processing program.
In our case the software we wanna use is Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We - from Hypriot - created a preconfigured &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;SD card image&lt;/a&gt; which contains everything you need to run Docker on your Raspberry Pi.
To use the image you first have to download and transfer it to your SD card. Transferring an image to an SD card is often referred to as &lt;em&gt;flashing&lt;/em&gt;.
Afterwards you just have to insert the flashed SD card into your Raspberry Pi and start it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-the-hypriot-docker-sd-card-image&#34;&gt;Download the Hypriot Docker SD card image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our latest SD card image from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the download is completed open a terminal window. To do this press &lt;strong&gt;CMD&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;Whitespace&lt;/strong&gt; and type &lt;em&gt;terminal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we will extract the downloaded zip file. Go to your &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt; folder first by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/Downloads
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now extract the zip file with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;unzip hypriotos-rpi-201???.img.zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the file is unzipped you will have a new file with an &lt;strong&gt;.img&lt;/strong&gt; extension.
In the next step we will flash this file onto your SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flash-the-downloaded-image-to-your-sd-card&#34;&gt;Flash the downloaded image to your SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First put your SD card into the computer. Then in the terminal type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;diskutil list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see a list of all your disks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/diskutil-list.png&#34; alt=&#34;disktuil-list&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now identify the SD card. Look at the fourth column which shows the size of the devices of your workstation.
One item in the list should have a size that is very close to the size of your SD card.
From there get the identifier which is shown in the first column.
Here the identifier is &lt;code&gt;/dev/disk5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now unmount the SD card. Make sure to replace &lt;code&gt;/dev/disk5&lt;/code&gt; with the identifier of your sd card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;diskutil unmountdisk /dev/disk5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result you should see&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/unmount.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot unmounted&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are ready to flash the SD card. We are going to use the &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; command for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you execute the command below, make sure to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace the parameter after &lt;code&gt;if=&lt;/code&gt; with the path to the downloaded image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replace the parameter after &lt;code&gt;of=&lt;/code&gt; with the identifier of your SD card. Make sure you put a &lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; in front of &lt;code&gt;disk&lt;/code&gt; as you can see in the example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dd if=hypriotos-rpi-201???.img of=/dev/rdisk5 bs=1m
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this command is executed you won&amp;rsquo;t get any information about its progress.
Depending on your hardware and the performance of your SD card it can take up to five minutes to flash the image.
When the &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; is finished, you should get an output like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/dd-success.png&#34; alt=&#34;after-dd-success&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally unmount the SD card again in the same way as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-raspberry-pi-with-the-sd-card&#34;&gt;Start your Raspberry Pi with the SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boot your Raspberry Pi by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting the Raspberry Pi to your local network via an ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;putting the SD card into the designated slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugging in the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the last step your Raspberry Pi will boot and the LEDs should start blinking.
The very first boot will take one to three minutes as the file system will be resized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ensure-everything-works&#34;&gt;Ensure everything works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if Docker is actually running we need to log into the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to find out the IP address of your Raspberry Pi first.
If you are not sure what the IP-Address of your PI is, there are different ways of finding it out.
One way is to use the &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First identify the IP address of your own workstation. Type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ipconfig getifaddr en1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it does not report back an IP address, you are probably connected via cable to your network. Try &lt;code&gt;en0&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;en1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the following screenshot our IP address is &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.101&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/own-ip-address.png&#34; alt=&#34;own-ip-address&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then replace the IP address in front of the &lt;code&gt;/24&lt;/code&gt; with yours and type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -sP 192.168.0.100/24 | grep black-pearl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; command should show you the IP address of your Raspberry Pi.
If you get a blank line without an IP address your Raspberry Pi is probably not connected to the network.
Or there is a problem with the SD card which prevents the Raspberry Pi from booting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you found out the IP address establish a connection to the Raspberry Pi with the ssh command.
Replace the IP address after the &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; with the one of your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh pirate@192.168.178.10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are asked for the password type &lt;code&gt;hypriot&lt;/code&gt; and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you establish the connection you will be asked if you are sure that you want to connect to the Raspberry Pi - answer with &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything went fine you should now see the &lt;em&gt;HypriotOS&lt;/em&gt; command line prompt waiting for your input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/hypriot-ssh-prompt-after-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;hypriot-ssh-prompt-after-login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally check if the Docker Service is running by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;docker info&lt;/code&gt; command should look similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/mac-screenies/docker-info.png&#34; alt=&#34;docker-info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations! You have succeeded in getting Docker running on your Raspberry Pi!&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to continue your exploration of Docker with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device#going-wild-with-docker-what-can-you-actually-do-with-it:397c66ef19f9f061b6711d2e296cb276&#34;&gt;Getting Started Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-windows-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 20:16:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-windows-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This guide shows you how to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using a &lt;strong&gt;Windows workstation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not read the getting started guide about Docker on the Raspberry Pi yet you might wanna check it out first: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device&#34;&gt;Getting started on your ARM device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;hardware&lt;/strong&gt; you gonna need to follow along is a Raspberry Pi 1 or 2 and one SD card.
If you are going to use a Raspberry 2 you will have to use a microSD card - otherwise a normal SD card is sufficient.
We recommend a size of at least 4 GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SD card contains all the software which we are going to use on our Raspberry Pi.
With software we basically mean two things: first an operating system for your Raspberry Pi and second the software you as user would like to use - e.g. a browser or a word processing program.
In our case the software we wanna use is Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We - from Hypriot - created a preconfigured &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;SD card image&lt;/a&gt; which contains everything you need to run Docker on your Raspberry Pi.
To use the image you first have to download and transfer it to your SD card. Transferring an image to an SD card is often referred to as &lt;em&gt;flashing&lt;/em&gt;.
Afterwards you just have to insert the flashed SD card into your Raspberry Pi and start it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial you will need to install four applications which we are going to use later. Please follow the download links and install them. Note the installation remarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.7-zip.de&#34;&gt;7-Zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For extracting the compressed SD card image. &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Make sure you choose the download file that fits your workstations&amp;rsquo;s architecture (x32 vs. x64)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/&#34;&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For flashing the SD card image to the SD card. &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;During installation you will find a checkbox called &amp;ldquo;Start Pcap-Service at startup&amp;rdquo;. We recommend to disable it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the.earth.li/~sgtatham/putty/latest/x86/putty.exe&#34;&gt;Putty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For establishing a connection to the Raspberry Pi &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Just download it. No installation needed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/nmap.mirror/?source=typ_redirect&#34;&gt;Zenmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For identifying the IP address of your Raspberry Pi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-the-hypriot-docker-sd-card-image&#34;&gt;Download the Hypriot Docker SD card image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our latest SD card image from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next go to your &lt;strong&gt;Download&lt;/strong&gt; folder and extract the downloaded zip file by right-clicking on the file and then clicking on &lt;strong&gt;7-zip&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;extract here&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 7-zip is finished with extracting you will have a file with a &lt;strong&gt;.img&lt;/strong&gt; extension.
In the next step we will flash this file onto your SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flash-the-downloaded-image-to-your-sd-card&#34;&gt;Flash the downloaded image to your SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start the flashing process right-click on the &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt; application which we installed earlier and click on &lt;em&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/em&gt;. You will see a window asking for permissions. Grant them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with the &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s window opened, click on the blue folder icon and choose the Hypriot SD card image in your &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the blue folder button, you will find a dropdown menu in which you can select your SD card.
To double check the device letter open your Windows Explorer and locate the SD card drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/image-writer-opened.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-writer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally click on &lt;strong&gt;write&lt;/strong&gt; which will flash the SD card image to the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completion close &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt; and eject the SD card before removing it from its slot.
In order to eject the SD card use the &lt;em&gt;secure eject&lt;/em&gt; function in the menu next to your system clock.
This is usually in the very bottom right corner of your screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/eject-sd-card.png&#34; alt=&#34;eject-sd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-raspberry-pi-with-the-sd-card&#34;&gt;Start your Raspberry Pi with the SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boot your Raspberry Pi by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting the Raspberry Pi to your local network via an ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;putting the SD card into the designated slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugging in the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the last step your Raspberry Pi will boot and the LEDs should start blinking.
The very first boot will take one to three minutes as the file system will be resized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ensure-everything-works&#34;&gt;Ensure everything works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if Docker is actually running we need to log into the Raspberry Pi via &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to find out the IP address of your Raspberry Pi first.
This can be done with &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; which we installed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After starting &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; look for the field &lt;em&gt;Command&lt;/em&gt;.
Type the following command into this field but replace the IP address in front of &lt;code&gt;/24&lt;/code&gt; with your own and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -sP 192.168.0.100/24
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result you should see this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/zenmap-scan-result.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;zenmap-scan-result&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; list all active hosts within your local network.
In order to find the Raspberry Pi click the button &lt;em&gt;filter hosts&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom of the &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; and type in &lt;em&gt;black&lt;/em&gt;.
Now the first line of the list should show the IP address of your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/zenmap-with-filter-with-marker.png&#34; alt=&#34;zenmap-with-filter-with-marker&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we now know where to find the Raspberry Pi within your network it is time to start &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt; to establish a SSH connection to your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After starting &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt; type in the IP address we determined into the field &lt;em&gt;Host Name&lt;/em&gt;. With a click on the button &lt;em&gt;Open&lt;/em&gt; the connection will be established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot-putty-login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new window which just opened type &lt;code&gt;pirate&lt;/code&gt; as login name and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;. Next you will be asked for a password. Type &lt;code&gt;hypriot&lt;/code&gt; and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything went fine you should now see the &lt;em&gt;HypriotOS&lt;/em&gt; command line prompt waiting for your input. It should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;putty-window-login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally to check if the Docker service is running type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;docker info&lt;/code&gt; command should look similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-docker-info.png&#34; alt=&#34;docker-info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations! You have succeeded in getting Docker running on your Raspberry Pi!&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to continue your exploration of Docker with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device#going-wild-with-docker-what-can-you-actually-do-with-it:397c66ef19f9f061b6711d2e296cb276&#34;&gt;Getting Started Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brand new Getting-Started guide for Docker on the Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/brand-new-getting-started-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 12:35:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/brand-new-getting-started-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last couple of days Mathias Renner and I were busy creating a comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started guide for Docker on the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;.
Our goal was to give users easy to understand step by step instructions on how to get Docker running on a Raspberry Pi.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually - in the end - we came up with three guides. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our HypriotOS SD card image we show Mac, Linux and Windows users individually how to use it on their operating system.
Downloading, flashing and booting up the SD card image on your Raspberry Pi is now easy as pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no excuses anymore not to try it - even for novice Raspberry Pi &amp;amp; Docker users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we get lots of feedback to make the guides even better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govinda &amp;amp; Mathias&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>