<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</title>
    <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/tags/windows/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.hypriot.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Close Encounters of the Third Kind, or Microsoft Windows meets Docker ARM Containers for IoT</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/close-encounters-of-the-third-kind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 17:20:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/close-encounters-of-the-third-kind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running an ARM-based Docker container for IoT applications directly on Microsoft Windows
looks like an unbelievable &lt;strong&gt;extraterrestrial technology&lt;/strong&gt; from outer space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cannot be true, it must be a fake, right?&lt;br /&gt;
Or, is this maybe just a &lt;strong&gt;cheap magic trick&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/close-encounters-of-the-third-kind/docker4win-arm-webpage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker for Windows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, believe me, that&amp;rsquo;s really true&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;behind-the-scenes&#34;&gt;Behind the scenes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I showed in my last blog post about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/post/first-touch-down-with-docker-for-mac/&#34;&gt;First Touch Down with Docker for Mac&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;ldquo;Docker for Mac&amp;rdquo; uses an Alpine Linux VM under the hood with the capability of emulating
ARM binaries on Intel CPUs. Because of &amp;ldquo;Docker for Windows&amp;rdquo; uses exactly the same
Alpine Linux in a Hyper-V virtual machine, this should work on Windows 10, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem here is, that the bind-mounting of a single binary doesn&amp;rsquo;t work
right now on Windows. I guess this will be fixed in a later release for sure. But
we can easily prepare an ARM-based Docker container to make the magic happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just have to put the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QEMU&#34;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt; emulator binary
into the Docker container, and as long as we
place it at the correct path &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/qemu-arm-static&lt;/code&gt;, this should work. The easiest
way to include the binary to the correct folder is to create a tar archive and use
the ADD command in the Dockerfile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;tar vtf qemu-arm-static.tar
drwxr-xr-x  0 dieter staff       0 Mar 28 18:34 usr/
drwxr-xr-x  0 dieter staff       0 Mar 28 18:34 usr/bin/
-rwxr-xr-x  0 dieter staff 2899840 Mar 28 18:34 usr/bin/qemu-arm-static
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;dockerfile&#34;&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;FROM hypriot/rpi-busybox-httpd
ADD qemu-arm-static.tar /
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this easy preparation we&amp;rsquo;re able to start an ARM-based Docker container on
Windows 10 with two steps only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Create the modified Docker image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker build -t rpi-busybox-httpd .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Start the QEMU-enabled Docker container&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -d -p 80:80 rpi-busybox-httpd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in this screenshot you can see all the necessary steps we need, there is really
nothing else to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/close-encounters-of-the-third-kind/docker4win-arm-container.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker for Windows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voilà&lt;/strong&gt; - that was the magic trick which can be applied to almost all ARM-based Docker
images to make them run in &amp;ldquo;Docker for Windows&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Docker for Mac&amp;rdquo; even on an Intel-based
CPU architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;watch-the-results&#34;&gt;Watch the results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Docker for Windows&amp;rdquo; publishes the Docker Engine network with the local network name
&lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt;. Thus to access the ARM web server, which is running inside of a Linux container,
 we just have to point our preferred web browser to &lt;code&gt;http://docker/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/close-encounters-of-the-third-kind/docker4win-arm-webpage2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker for Windows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Docker for Windows&amp;rdquo; uses Windows native hypervisor Hyper-V&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Docker Engine is running in a tiny Alpine Linux VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM-based Docker containers can be easily enabled with QEMU emulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker works great on Windows 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you curious now and want to get in touch with &amp;ldquo;Docker for Windows&amp;rdquo; by yourself?
Then you should register for the Docker BETA program at &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.docker.com&#34;&gt;https://beta.docker.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send us your feedback on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/hypriot/talk&#34;&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; or tweet your thoughts and ideas on this project at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HypriotTweets&#34;&gt;@HypriotTweets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dieter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Quintus23M&#34;&gt;@Quintus23M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kitematic meets Windows Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/kitematic-meets-windows-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:07:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/post/kitematic-meets-windows-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just want to share some screenshots with you. Today I have played with Kitematic on a Windows Server 2016 TP3 and made it talk to the Windows Docker Engine. Yes, no VirtualBox in between. Just starting native Windows Containers from the Kitematic interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/kitematic-meets-windows-docker/kitematic-win2016tp3.png-shadow.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A closer look at the left column shows a running &lt;strong&gt;mongo&lt;/strong&gt; container. Yes, I know, you cannot pull docker images with the Windows Docker Engine at the moment. But I have built a mongo Docker image for Windows with this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StefanScherer/dockerfiles-windows/blob/master/mongo/3.0/Dockerfile&#34;&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/a&gt; and created the container by pressing the &lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; button in the Kitematic UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/kitematic-meets-windows-docker/kitematic-mongo.png-shadow.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to show that this is no fake you can see some windows paths in the container logs view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/kitematic-meets-windows-docker/kitematic-list.png-shadow.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always use the comments below to give us feedback and share it on Twitter or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stefan&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-windows-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 20:16:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-and-windows-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This guide shows you how to get Docker running on your Raspberry Pi using a &lt;strong&gt;Windows workstation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not read the getting started guide about Docker on the Raspberry Pi yet you might wanna check it out first: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device&#34;&gt;Getting started on your ARM device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;hardware&lt;/strong&gt; you gonna need to follow along is a Raspberry Pi 1 or 2 and one SD card.
If you are going to use a Raspberry 2 you will have to use a microSD card - otherwise a normal SD card is sufficient.
We recommend a size of at least 4 GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SD card contains all the software which we are going to use on our Raspberry Pi.
With software we basically mean two things: first an operating system for your Raspberry Pi and second the software you as user would like to use - e.g. a browser or a word processing program.
In our case the software we wanna use is Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We - from Hypriot - created a preconfigured &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;SD card image&lt;/a&gt; which contains everything you need to run Docker on your Raspberry Pi.
To use the image you first have to download and transfer it to your SD card. Transferring an image to an SD card is often referred to as &lt;em&gt;flashing&lt;/em&gt;.
Afterwards you just have to insert the flashed SD card into your Raspberry Pi and start it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial you will need to install four applications which we are going to use later. Please follow the download links and install them. Note the installation remarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.7-zip.de&#34;&gt;7-Zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For extracting the compressed SD card image. &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Make sure you choose the download file that fits your workstations&amp;rsquo;s architecture (x32 vs. x64)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/&#34;&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For flashing the SD card image to the SD card. &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;During installation you will find a checkbox called &amp;ldquo;Start Pcap-Service at startup&amp;rdquo;. We recommend to disable it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the.earth.li/~sgtatham/putty/latest/x86/putty.exe&#34;&gt;Putty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For establishing a connection to the Raspberry Pi &lt;/br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Just download it. No installation needed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/nmap.mirror/?source=typ_redirect&#34;&gt;Zenmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For identifying the IP address of your Raspberry Pi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-the-hypriot-docker-sd-card-image&#34;&gt;Download the Hypriot Docker SD card image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our latest SD card image from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next go to your &lt;strong&gt;Download&lt;/strong&gt; folder and extract the downloaded zip file by right-clicking on the file and then clicking on &lt;strong&gt;7-zip&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;extract here&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 7-zip is finished with extracting you will have a file with a &lt;strong&gt;.img&lt;/strong&gt; extension.
In the next step we will flash this file onto your SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flash-the-downloaded-image-to-your-sd-card&#34;&gt;Flash the downloaded image to your SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start the flashing process right-click on the &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt; application which we installed earlier and click on &lt;em&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/em&gt;. You will see a window asking for permissions. Grant them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with the &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s window opened, click on the blue folder icon and choose the Hypriot SD card image in your &lt;em&gt;Download&lt;/em&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the blue folder button, you will find a dropdown menu in which you can select your SD card.
To double check the device letter open your Windows Explorer and locate the SD card drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/image-writer-opened.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-writer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally click on &lt;strong&gt;write&lt;/strong&gt; which will flash the SD card image to the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon completion close &lt;em&gt;Win32 Disk Imager&lt;/em&gt; and eject the SD card before removing it from its slot.
In order to eject the SD card use the &lt;em&gt;secure eject&lt;/em&gt; function in the menu next to your system clock.
This is usually in the very bottom right corner of your screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/eject-sd-card.png&#34; alt=&#34;eject-sd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-your-raspberry-pi-with-the-sd-card&#34;&gt;Start your Raspberry Pi with the SD card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boot your Raspberry Pi by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connecting the Raspberry Pi to your local network via an ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;putting the SD card into the designated slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugging in the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the last step your Raspberry Pi will boot and the LEDs should start blinking.
The very first boot will take one to three minutes as the file system will be resized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ensure-everything-works&#34;&gt;Ensure everything works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if Docker is actually running we need to log into the Raspberry Pi via &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to find out the IP address of your Raspberry Pi first.
This can be done with &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; which we installed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After starting &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; look for the field &lt;em&gt;Command&lt;/em&gt;.
Type the following command into this field but replace the IP address in front of &lt;code&gt;/24&lt;/code&gt; with your own and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -sP 192.168.0.100/24
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result you should see this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/zenmap-scan-result.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;zenmap-scan-result&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; list all active hosts within your local network.
In order to find the Raspberry Pi click the button &lt;em&gt;filter hosts&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom of the &lt;em&gt;Zenmap&lt;/em&gt; and type in &lt;em&gt;black&lt;/em&gt;.
Now the first line of the list should show the IP address of your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/zenmap-with-filter-with-marker.png&#34; alt=&#34;zenmap-with-filter-with-marker&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we now know where to find the Raspberry Pi within your network it is time to start &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt; to establish a SSH connection to your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After starting &lt;em&gt;PuTTY&lt;/em&gt; type in the IP address we determined into the field &lt;em&gt;Host Name&lt;/em&gt;. With a click on the button &lt;em&gt;Open&lt;/em&gt; the connection will be established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot-putty-login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new window which just opened type &lt;code&gt;pirate&lt;/code&gt; as login name and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;. Next you will be asked for a password. Type &lt;code&gt;hypriot&lt;/code&gt; and hit &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything went fine you should now see the &lt;em&gt;HypriotOS&lt;/em&gt; command line prompt waiting for your input. It should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;putty-window-login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally to check if the Docker service is running type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output of the &lt;code&gt;docker info&lt;/code&gt; command should look similar to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/images/blog_post_getting-started/windows-screenies/putty-window-docker-info.png&#34; alt=&#34;docker-info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations! You have succeeded in getting Docker running on your Raspberry Pi!&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to continue your exploration of Docker with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hypriot.com/getting-started-with-docker-on-your-arm-device#going-wild-with-docker-what-can-you-actually-do-with-it:397c66ef19f9f061b6711d2e296cb276&#34;&gt;Getting Started Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>